[
  {
    "id": "1733",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni was commanded by his father_____, to write upon the plates to preserve their genealogy.",
    "answer": ["Jarom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1734",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni in his days; would that ye should know that “I fought much with the_____, to preserve my people, the Nephites”.",
    "answer": ["Sword"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1735",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Omni fought much with the sword to preserve the Nephites from falling into the hands of their enemies, the Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1736",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:1",
    "question": "Who wrote: “But behold, I myself am a wicked man, and I have not kept the statutes and the commandments of the Lord as I ought to have done”?",
    "answer": ["Omni"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1737",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:2",
    "question": "Omni was not a wicked man, and obeyed all the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1738",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Omni wrote that they had six seasons of peace; and had many_____ of serious war and bloodshed.",
    "answer": ["Seasons"],
    "options": ["Seasons", "Times", "Years"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1739",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Omni only wrote three verses in the Book of Omni.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1740",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Who did Omni confer the plates to?",
    "answer": ["Amaron"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1741",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:3",
    "question": "Amaron was the son of what Book of Mormon historian?",
    "answer": ["Omni"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1742",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:4",
    "question": "Amaron tells us that he wrote only a few words in the book of his father.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1743",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that three hundred and twenty years had passed away, and the more wicked part of the_____ were destroyed.",
    "answer": ["Nephites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1744",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:6",
    "question": "The Lord would not suffer that his words should not be verified, when he said to Omni’s fathers:  “Inasmuch as ye will not keep my _____ ye shall not prosper in the land”.",
    "answer": ["Commandments"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1745",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord visited the Nephites in great_____.",
    "answer": ["Judgment"],
    "options": ["Numbers", "Power", "Judgment"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1746",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord did spare the righteous that they should not perish.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1747",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:7",
    "question": "The Lord did spare the_____ Nephites that they should not perish and delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": ["Righteous"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1748",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:8",
    "question": "Who was the brother of Omni that he delivered the plates to?",
    "answer": ["Chemish"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1749",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian only wrote one verse in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": ["Chemish"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1750",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "Chemish wrote that his brother Omni wrote on the plates on the same day that he delivered the plates unto him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1751",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:9",
    "question": "Chemish wrote that he saw the last which his brother wrote, and that he wrote it with his own hand.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1752",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:10-11",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon record keeper wrote only two versus in the Book of Omni?",
    "answer": ["Abinadom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1753",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1-10",
    "question": "Who was the son of Chemish, who was also a record keeper?",
    "answer": ["Abinadom"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1754",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:10",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that he had taken the lives of many of Lamanites by using what kind of weapon?",
    "answer": ["Sword"],
    "options": ["Sword", "Cimeter", "Sling"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1755",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:11",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that the record of the Lamanites is engraved upon the plates which is had by the kings.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1756",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:11",
    "question": "Abinadom wrote that he knew of no revelation save that which has been written, neither prophecy; so he did not write anymore.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1757",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "What record keeper of the Book of Mormon was the son of Abinadom?",
    "answer": ["Amaleki"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1758",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Amaleki was the last record keeper to write in the Book of Omni.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1759",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "In what book is the prophet Mosiah first mentioned?",
    "answer": ["Omni"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1760",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "Amaleki spoke concerning Mosiah, who was made king over the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1761",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "In the Book of Omni: What king of Zarahemla was warned of the Lord to flee out of the land of Nephi?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1762",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "The Lord told Mosiah to flee out of the land of Nephi, and to take as many of the Nephites that would hearken unto him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1763",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:12",
    "question": "Where did the Lord tell Mosiah and his people to go when they fled out of the land of Nephi?",
    "answer": ["Wilderness"],
    "options": ["Forest", "Wilderness", "Another City"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1764",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass, that Mosiah did not do according to what the Lord had commanded of him.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1765",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his followers were led by preachings and prophesyings.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1766",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and the Nephites were admonished continually by the word of _____.",
    "answer": ["God"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1767",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his people were led by the power of the_____ of God through the wilderness.",
    "answer": ["Arm"],
    "options": ["Arm", "Word", "Mercy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1768",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:13",
    "question": "Mosiah and his people were led by the arm of God into the land which is called the land of_____.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1769",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Mosiah discovered a people who were called the people of____.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zoram", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1770",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "When Mosiah arrived in the land of Zarahemla, there was not any rejoicing or happiness.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1771",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Who rejoiced exceedingly because the Lord had sent the people of Mosiah with the plates of brass?",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1772",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:14",
    "question": "Zarahemla did rejoice because the plates conta1ned the record of the Jews.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1774",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "Mosiah discovered that the people of Zarahemla came out from Jerusalem.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1775",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla came out from Jerusalem at the time that Zedekiah, king of Judah, was carried away captive into Babylon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1776",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:15",
    "question": "Zedekiah was the king of_____, when he was carried away captive into Babylon.",
    "answer": ["Judah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1777",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:16",
    "question": "Zarahemla and his people were brought by the hand of the Lord across the____ waters, into the land where Mosiah discovered them.",
    "answer": ["Great"],
    "options": ["Many", "Great", "Deep"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1778",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "At the time that Mosiah discovered them, the people of Zarahemla had become exceedingly numerous.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1779",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla had had many wars and serious contentions, and had fallen by the_____ from time to time.",
    "answer": ["Sword"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1780",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The language of the people of Zarahemla had become corrupted; and they had brought no records with them.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1781",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "The people of Zarahemla did not deny the being of their Creator.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1782",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:17",
    "question": "Because of the language that they spoke:  _____ neither the people of Mosiah, could not understand them.",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1783",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "What prophet caused the people of Zarahemla to be taught in the language of the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1784",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Mosiah caused that the people of Zarahemla were taught in the language of Mosiah.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1785",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "After Zarahemla was taught in the language of Mosiah, he gave a genealogy of his_____.",
    "answer": ["Fathers"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1786",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "Zarahemla gave a genealogy of his fathers according to his memory.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1787",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:18",
    "question": "Zarahemla gave a genealogy of his fathers according to his memory; and they are written but not on the plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1788",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of_____, and of Mosiah united together.",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla-"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1789",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:19",
    "question": "Who was appointed king over the people of Zarahemla and of the people of Mosiah?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1790",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "In the days of Mosiah, there was a small stone brought to him with engravings on it.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1791",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the days of Mosiah, there was a large stone brought unto him with_____ on it.",
    "answer": ["Engravings"],
    "options": ["Writings", "Hieroglyphics", "Engravings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1792",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:20",
    "question": "Mosiah did interpret the engravings on the large stone by the gift and_____ of God.",
    "answer": ["Power"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1793",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The large stone that Mosiah interpreted gave an account of_____, and the slain of his people.",
    "answer": ["Coriantumr"],
    "options": ["Zoram", "Coriantumr", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1795",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The large stone that Mosiah interpreted gave an account of_____ and the slain of his people.",
    "answer": ["Coriantumr"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1796",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The stone that Mosiah interpreted did not give an account of Coriantumr or the slain of his people.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1797",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "By what people was Coriantumr discovered?",
    "answer": ["Zarahemla"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1798",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "Coriantumr dwelt with the people of Zarahemla for the space of n1ne_____.",
    "answer": ["Moons"],
    "options": ["Moons", "Years", "Days"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1799",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "The word moons; only appears once in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1800",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:21",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book can we find the word Moons?",
    "answer": ["Omni"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1801",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon speaks of the Tower of Babel by name.-",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1802",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "Coriantumr’s first parents came out from the tower, at the time the Lord confounded the language of the people",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1803",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The severity of the Lord fell upon Coriantumr’s people, according to his judgments, which are_____.",
    "answer": ["Just"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1804",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:22",
    "question": "The bones of the people of Coriantumr are scattered in the land_____.",
    "answer": ["Northward"],
    "options": ["Eastward", "Northward", "Southward"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1805",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "In the Book of Omni, what Book of Mormon historian was born in the days of King Mosiah?",
    "answer": ["Ameleki"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1806",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "What Book of Omni record keeper lived to see the days of King Mosiah and also his death?",
    "answer": ["Amaleki"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1807",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "Who did the record keeper Amaleki say reign after the death of his father?",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1808",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "Amaleki said that in the days of King Benjamin he had seen a serious war and much bloodshed between the Nephites and Lamanites.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1809",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "During the days of King Benjamin, the Nephites obta1ned much advantage over the_____ according to Ameleki.",
    "answer": ["Lamanites"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1810",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:24",
    "question": "King Benjamin did not drive the Lamanites out of the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": ["False"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1811",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "The record keeper Ameleki; did not have any seed.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1812",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki testified that he knew King_____ was a just man before the Lord.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1813",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Who did Ameleki deliver the plates to? Exhorting all men to come unto God, the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": ["Benjamin"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1814",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to believe in prophesying, and in revelations, and in the ministering of_____.",
    "answer": ["Angels"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1815",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to believe in the gift of speaking with tongues, and the gift of interpreting languages, and in all things which are good.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1816",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:25",
    "question": "Who is the first person in the Book of Mormon to say? “For there is nothing which is good save it comes from the Lord; and that which is evil cometh from the devil”.",
    "answer": ["Ameleki"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1817",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "And now my beloved brethren, I would that ye should come, unto_____, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his salvation.",
    "answer": ["Christ"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1818",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki wanted us to come unto Christ, who is the Holy One of Israel, and partake of his_____ and the power of his redemption.",
    "answer": ["Salvation"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1819",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki wants us to come unto Christ and offer our whole_____ as an offering to him.",
    "answer": ["Souls"],
    "options": ["Bodies", "Tithes", "Souls"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1820",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:26",
    "question": "Ameleki writes that we should continue in fasting and praying, and endure to the end; and as the Lord lives we will be saved.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1821",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:27& 2Nep:2",
    "question": "Ameleki said that there were a certain number of people who went to the land of Nephi, and were desirous to possess the land of their inheritance.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1822",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:28",
    "question": "Ameleki writes that the people that went up unto the wilderness had a leader who was a strong and_____ man, wherefore he caused a contention among them.",
    "answer": ["Mighty"],
    "options": ["Mighty", "Awful", "Delightsome"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1824",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Ameleki wrote that he had a brother that went with Zefiff and has not since known concerning them or him.",
    "answer": ["True"],
    "options": ["True", "False"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1825",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:30",
    "question": "Ameleki wrote that the_____ were full and that he was about to lie down in his grave.",
    "answer": ["Plates"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1878",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Omni1:23",
    "question": "What was the name of King Benjamin’s father?",
    "answer": ["Mosiah"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1823",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Omni1:28, Mos7:21, Mos9:3-4",
    "question": "The strong and mighty man that went up to the wilderness was_____.",
    "answer": ["Zeniff"],
    "options": ["Nephi", "Zeniff", "Zenos"]
  }
]
